嘿  嘿
Hey.  Hey.
等我一下
Hold on a second.
厉害  厉害
Nice. Nice.
有东西要给你
I got you something.
这是什么  812块钱
What's this?  Eight hundred and twelve bucks.
老鸨没告诉你吗  要一千块
I don't know what Big Leon told you, but it's a thousand...
如果要我过一整夜的话
...if you want me for the whole night.
这是在干嘛啊  哦  我现在有在赚钱了
What is this for? Well, I'm making money now.
这是要还你拍大头照的钱  电费
And this is paying you back for headshots, electric bills...
还有数不清的披萨的钱
...and so many slices of pizza I can't even count.
我爱你  老兄  哦  谢了  老兄
I love you, man.  Well, thanks, man.
这下子我可以买小马了
Now I can get my pony.
这是我小小的心意  谢谢你一直陪在我身边
Hey. This is a little extra something for always being there for me.
哇  我不晓得该说什么才好
Wow, I don't know what to say.
你觉得怎样  我不知道
Eh? What do you say? I don't know.
这是一条手链
It's a bracelet.
可不是吗  还有刻字  快看看
Isn't it? It's engraved too. Check it out.
〝送给我的好哥儿〞
"To my best bud."
谢了  好哥儿
Thanks, best bud.
戴上去  现在吗
Put it on. Oh. Now?
不  这种好货色应该留着  等重大场合才戴
No, something this nice should be saved for a special occasion.
不  最棒的就在这儿  这手链什么场合都能用
No, that's the beauty part. It goes with everything.
只要戴上去  就可风风光光的出门
When you put this on, you're good to go.
哦  哇
Oh, man!
你真适合戴手链
You are so wearing that bracelet!
我真的咧
I so am!
知道这种东东  会为你的性生活带来什么好处
Oh! Any idea what this will do for your sex life?
一开始可能会让我速度变慢…
It'll probably slow it down at first...
等我习惯这种重量之后  就可回归常轨
...but once I'm used to the extra weight, I'll be back on track.
《老友记》 第二季 第14集: 毕业舞会录影带
Friends S02E14: The One With the Prom Video
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
看起来都很棒  太好了
This all looks good.  Great.
如果我想找人问问  你过去的工作表现呢
If I want to call for a reference on your last job?
就在那边  经理是钱德宾
Oh, that's there on the bottom, see? The manager, Chandler Bing?
好的
All right.
我们就来看看你本人有没有纸上写的那么好  给我做个沙拉
Let's see if you're as good in person as you are on paper. Make me a salad.
（制片：塔德·史帝文斯）
沙拉   我可以做更复杂的东西
A salad? I could do something more complicated.
（制片：贝西·伯恩斯）
不  沙拉就可以了
No, just the salad will be fine.
（编剧：艾利沙·强奇）
没问题
You got it.
可是我要你一边做一边告诉我你正在做什么
Now I want you to tell me what you're doing while you're doing it.
（导演：詹姆斯·柏洛斯）
好的  哦  我在撕莴苣
All right. Well, I'm tearing the lettuce.
莴苣很脏吗
Uh-huh. Is it dirty?
放心好了  我会清洗的
Oh, no, no. I'm gonna wash it.
不要  我喜欢脏脏的
Don't. I like it dirty.
悉听尊便了
That's your call.
你接下来要做什么呢
So, uh, what are you going to do next?
我想我要切蕃茄
I thought that I'd cut up the tomatoes.
蕃茄很坚挺吗
Are they firm?
还可以  你确定没有变坏吗
They're okay.  You sure they haven't gone bad?
你确定  都没有很坏  很坏吗
You sure they're not very, very bad?
不  都可以啦
Ahem. No, really, they're okay.
你会切片切得很好吗
You gonna slice them up real nice?
事实上  我打算切成丝
I was going to do them julienne.
我不干了
I'm out of here!
喂
Hello?
瑞秋不在  需要我转达什么吗
Rachel's not here right now. Can I take a message?
是哪个凯西
All right. And how do we spell Casey?
是《凯西出击》 或是《凯希阳光合唱团》那个
Is it like "at the bat" or "and The Sunshine Band"?
好  再见
Okay, bye-bye.
嘿  这个凯西是谁啊
Hey, who's this Casey?
一个她看电影时遇到的家伙
Some guy she met at the movies.
他要找她干嘛
What does he want with her?
我猜他想跟她跳点小舞
I'm guessing he wants to do a little dance...
也就是去〝嘿咻一下〞
...you know, make a little love...
哦  也就等于是 〝上床〞去
Well, pretty much get down tonight.
我不晓得  我不…
I don't know. I don't...
我不懂  两个月前  我跟瑞秋还很亲密
I don't get it! Two months ago, Rachel and I were this close.
现在我却在帮一个  她看电影时遇到的家伙留话
Now I'm taking messages from guys she meets at the movies?
这个凯西才该帮我留言  你们知道吗
I mean, this Casey should be taking down my messages, you know?
瑞秋和我才应该在一起…
Or Rachel and I should be together...
然后我们一起请电话秘书
...and we should get some kind of message service.
等等吧  会有那么一天的
Hang in there. It's gonna happen.
你怎么知道
Now how do you know that?
因为她是你的龙虾
Because she's your lobster.
哦  她会说明的
Oh, she's going somewhere.
龙虾都会爱上一生的伴侣  这是常识
It's a known fact that lobsters fall in love and mate for life.
知道吗  我们真的可以目睹  年老的龙虾夫妇…
You know what? You can actually see old lobster couples...
在他们的水槽里  钳子牵着钳子漫步  就像这样…
...walking around their tank, holding claws, like...
有觉得好一点了吗
Hey, you feeling better?
我想洗到第五次  就可以把面试的记忆冲掉了
Yeah, I think that fifth shower actually got the interview off me.
你还有别的机会吗
So do you have any other possibilities?
我是有机会付不出房租
Yeah. There is the possibility that I won't make rent.
摩妮卡  如果你想要  我可以借你一点钱
Monica, if you want, I can lend you money.
不  不  如果我无法立刻还你钱
No, no. If I couldn't pay you back right away...
每次见到你  我就会感到充满罪恶感与压力
...then I'd feel guilty and tense every time I saw you.
何不直接找爸爸妈妈借
Oh. Then why don't you borrow it from Mom and Dad?
反正你在他们面前  已经充满罪恶感与压力了
You feel guilty and tense around them already.
何不顺便捞点钱出来
Might as well make some money off of them.
说的有理
The man's got a point. Ohh.
那闪闪发亮的是什么东东
What is that sparkly thing?
这玩意儿
That thing? It's a, uh...
对  是有点俗气
Yeah, it's a little flashy.
不  不会
No, no.
不  不俗气的  高凌风来戴正好
No, no. It's not flashy. Not for a goodfella.
太正点了  你一定有给它〝闲〞很多钱吧
Man, that is sharp! That must have cost you quite a few doubloons.
嗨  嗨
Hi.  Hi.
亲爱的  这是什么
Hi, darling. So what's this?
你的一些旧东西
Some of your old stuff.
哦  亲爱的  我们要给你一个惊喜
Well, sweetie, we have a surprise for you.
我们要把你的房间变成健身房
We're turning your room into a gym.
哇  真是没想到
Wow, that is a surprise!
容我问一下  干嘛不用罗斯的房间
Just one little question. Why not Ross' room?
我们是有讨论过了…
Gosh, we talked about that...
可是他有太多  科学类的奖杯  奖状  奖章这类的
...but your brother had so many science trophies, plaques, merit badges...
我们不想去动到
Well, we didn't want to disturb them.
万万不可
God forbid!
哦  嗨
Ohh.  Hi.
嗨  瑞秋
Hi, Rachel. Aww.
很遗憾我们听说  你的父母分手了
We were so sorry to hear about your parents splitting up.
哦  他们才刚分居而已  还说不定  我们等着瞧就是
Well, they're just separated. You never know! We'll see.
我是不能说感到惊讶
I can't say any of us were surprised.
从我们认识他们之后  就没看他们快乐过
Your parents have been unhappy ever since we've known them.
特别是在夏威夷出状况后
Oh. Especially after that incident in Hawaii.
什么  什么状况
What? What incident?
不  不  我一定是想错人了
Um, no, no. I must be thinking of someone else.
搞不好是我自己
Maybe me! Ha!
你不是有衣服要摺吗  去摺  亲爱的  你去忙
Don't you have some folding to do? Go fold, dear. Fold. You fold.
要续杯吗  我不要了  谢谢
Want a refill? No. I'm all right, thanks.
等我一下下  我要演得很像
You gotta give me a second. I want to get this just right.
恩
Ahem.
兄弟  十一点方向  无敌辣妹一直在看你
Dude, 11:00, totally hot babe checking you out.
真的很棒  我想我可以去变性了
That was really good. I think I'm ready for my penis now.
我知道你误认我为何许人  大卫汤玛斯  温蒂的创办人
I know what you're thinking. Dave Thomas, founder of Wendy's.
我是盖儿  钱德
I'm Gail.  Chandler.
我真的得走了  真是幸会了
I... I really have to be somewhere, but it was nice meeting you.
什么
What?
太棒了
This is excellent!
他大可送我一台录影机或高尔夫球杆
He could've gotten me a VCR or a set of golf clubs.
但他没有  他却给我弄了个 〝女性终结者〞
But no! He has to get me the "woman repeller"!
什么〝T先生的废物之屋〞 出品的丑东西
The eyesore from the Liberace House of Crap!
没那么糟  你说的倒容易
It's not that bad.  Easy for you to say.
你又不用戴着  连T先生都不要的东西到处走
You're not sporting a reject from the Mr. T collection!
钱德…
Chandler. Chandler.
〝我同情那些戴着我的珠宝的傻瓜  我真的同情〞
"I pity the fool that puts on my jewelry! I do! I do!
〝我同情那些戴着…〞 嗨
I pity that fool..." Ay.
嘿  兄弟  我们刚刚在玩模仿秀
Hey, man! We were just doing some impressions.
模仿你的马歇马叟
Do your Marcel Marceau.
演得还不错
That's actually good.
你看看那家伙
Would you look at that guy?
他跟她已经聊多久了
How long has he been talking to her?
真想说〝滚开  臭家伙  她是服务生又不是艺妓〞
It's like, back off, buddy! She's a waitress, not a geisha.
我想她很愉快
I think she's okay.
你看看  她都推开他了  他还死不走
Look at that! See how she's pushing him away and he won't budge?
我得采取行动才行
I'm gonna do something.
我们可以在山上租间木屋  滑进滑出的  很棒
We'll get a condo right on the mountain. Ski in, ski out, it's great.
抱歉  你是瑞秋吗
Excuse me? Are you Rachel?
干嘛
What?
我是罗斯盖勒
Ross Geller.
老天  你在广告上有写到  你很美  不过  哇
God, in your ad you said you were pretty, but wow!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
哦  我的天  你今天不行吗
Oh, my God, is this the wrong day?
我真不敢相信
I don't believe it!
如果行的话  我们就能对后代子孙好好吹嘘一番了
If it works out, we'll have something to tell the grandkids!
你会有机会的
You sure will.
我得走了
I've gotta go.
后会有期  好
Take care. Okay.
再见了 很高兴认识你
See you later. Ohh.
不客气
You're welcome.
什么  我是在救你
What?  I was saving you.
好让我结束跟一个迷人男子很开心的对话
Saving me from the pleasant conversation with the interesting man?
从我刚才坐的位置看来…  罗斯，听我说
From where I was... Okay, Ross, listen to me.
我不用你救
I am not yours to save.
但是  你要…  什么
But you are. What?
你是我的龙虾
Uh, well, um... You're my lobster.
你又在玩盲目约会的游戏了
Okay. Are you being the blind-date guy again?
不  你是我的龙虾
No, you're my lobster.
龙虾呢…
See, um... Lobsters...
在水槽里  他们变老了以后…
Uh, in the tank, when they're old...
会那个… 他们会牵着钳子散步
...they get with the... They walk around holding the claws.
在水槽里
In the tank! You know, with...
牵着钳子而且…
...with the holding and...
菲比  要来帮我说龙虾的事吗
Pheebs, you wanna help me with the lobster thing?
再做一次握的动作
Do the claws again.
瑞秋  别管龙虾了  可以吗
Rach, forget the lobsters, okay?
我们来谈谈… 谈谈我们如何
Let's talk... What about us?
罗斯  没有所谓的〝我们〞 可以吗
Ross, there is no "us," okay?
对  可是… 不  你听我说
No, but... - No! Listen to me!
我爱上你却深受打击
I fell for you and I get clobbered.
你爱上我  我还是深受打击
You then fall for me and I again get clobbered.
我不想再受伤了 你知道吗
I'm tired of being clobbered, you know?
不值得的
It's just not worth it.
嗯  可是…
Well, but...
没有〝可是〞了  罗斯
No "but," Ross.
我们是不可能的  好吗  接受吧
We are never gonna happen, okay? Accept that.
要我接受什么吗
Except... Except that what?
不  不
No. No.
接受这个事实吧
Accept that.
哦
Oh.
嘿  老兄  哇  是我的好哥儿  你好吗
Hey, man! Look, it's my best bud! How you doing?
你愈来愈会模仿马歇马叟了
Wow. You're getting good at that Marcel Marceau thing.
我们打打球如何  就你和我  你说什么
What do you say we play some ball? You and me, huh? What do you say?
好  是我不好
Okay, that's my bad.
如果你不喜欢那条手链  你大可直说
If you hated the bracelet, you should have just said so.
我有戴着不就表示
Doesn't the fact that I wore it...
我有多重视我们的友谊了
...say how much our friendship means to me?
那你羞辱那条手链  还有你还取笑我的事实呢
What about the fact that you insulted the bracelet and you made fun of me?
哦  那部分我倒是个王八蛋
Well, that's the part where I'm a wank.
希望我们不要  只注意那种小地方
I was hoping you wouldn't focus on that.
好啦  我说过几百遍我很抱歉了
Come on, man! I said I was sorry a hundred times.
我保证我再也不会拿下我的…
I promise, I will never take it off my...
手链
...wrist.
如果你想待在里面发脾气…
But if you want to stay in there and be mad...
那就待吧
...you just, you stay in there.
你知道吗…
You know what the...
我就在这里  跪着…
I am here, on my knees...
拿着这两个椅垫…
...holding up these couch cushions...
作为我悲伤与悔恨的象征
...as a symbol of my sorrow and regret.
就像《圣经》里的故事一样
Much like they did in biblical times.
你现在可以痛快的发泄了…
Though you may haveth anger now...
知道吗  葛拉芙真的很会叫
You know, that Steffi Graf has quite a tush.
我只是说说  你自己看
I'm just saying! It's right there!
嘿  大家好  嗨  亲爱的
Hey, guys. Hi, darling.
我的孙子呢  你没把他带来
Where's my grandson? You didn't bring him?
没  他今天在卡萝跟苏珊那里
No. He's at Carol and Susan's today.
我公司的一个女孩也是个同性恋
A woman in my office is a lesbian.
我只是说说
I'm just saying!
杰克  快看  你看了就会笑的那个油漆广告开始了
Jack, look! There's that house paint commercial that cracks you up!
你去哪里了  陷入情绪的地狱里
Where have you been?  Emotional hell.
他们有借你钱吗
So did they lend you the money?
没有  因为我还没开口
No, I haven't asked them yet.
得了  摩妮卡  快点
Come on, Monica, do it.
嘿  你们
Hey, you guys.
摩妮卡有事要说
Monica has some news.
很抱歉我没有早点告诉你们  可是…
So listen, I'm sorry I didn't tell you this before, but...
我已经辞职了  我不得不辞职
...I'm no longer at my job. I had to leave it.
为什么  被他们逼的
Why? Because they made me.
你被炒鱿鱼了  这下子该怎么办呢
You were fired? What are you gonna do?
茱蒂  别紧张  她可是我们的小小〝魔女卡〞
Judy, relax. This is our little Harmonica we're talking about.
我们把她教得很精
We taught her well.
你一成的薪水都会…  存银行
Ten percent of your paycheck goes where? In the bank.
她有在积少成多的  储蓄就是为此
So she dips into her savings. That's what it's there for.
她不会有事的
She's gonna be fine.
如果你不太够用
If you need a little extra...
你也知道该去哪里要
...you know where to find it.
有大张一点的吗
Anything larger back there?
真是难以置信
I can't believe it!
可以不要碎碎念了吗
Would you stop already?
就别再抱怨谷仓里的苦差事  跳到草堆里玩玩吧
Get out of the bitter barn and play in the hay.
没错  我是该跳到稻草堆里玩玩
Oh, you're right. I should play in the hay.
别忘了  我刚刚拿四百块换来一个  我一开始就很讨厌的手链
For about the fact I just dropped $400 to replace a bracelet I hated to begin with.
就拿稻草来给我玩玩吧
Bring on the hay!
嘿
Hey!
我有一个能让你很开心的东西
I've got something that'll make you happy.
你猜阿甘找到什么东西了
Guess what Gunther found?
喔
PHOEBE: Ohh!
这下子你有两个了
Hey, now you have two!
哦  你有两个哦
Oh, now you have two.
这下子我怎么办呢
What am I gonna do?
嘿
Hey.
你怎么会有两个
How come you have two?
这一个是给你的
This one's for you.
别闹了  不  我停不下来
Get out! No, I can't.
我知道这手链对你意义有多大
I know how much this means to you...
我也知道这不只是个首饰
...and I also know this is about more than jewelry.
这代表了你和我  代表我们是〝好哥儿们〞
It's about you and me and the fact that we're "best buds."
这代表友谊吗  我想是的
Wow. Is this friendship? I think so!
你看看  我们是手链好哥儿们
Check it out! We're bracelet buddies!
以后他们就会这样叫我们
That's what they'll call us!
好了  你什么时候还我都可以
Okay, here you go. Pay me back whenever you like.
你竟然有恐龙图案的支票
You have dinosaur checks?
对  你拿到钱的同时  还可以学些东西
Yeah. You get your money and you learn something.
有什么不好吗
What's wrong with that?
没有
Nothing.
嘿  你是只小气的恐龙
Hey, you're a cheap-a-saurus!
开玩笑的啦  谢了  感激不尽
I'm kidding, I'm kidding. Thank you, I'm very grateful.
嘿  摩妮卡  这是什么
Hey, Mon, what is this?
哦  恩
Oh, um...
我高中时的泳装  我当年比较肿一点
That's my bathing suit from high school. I was a little bigger then.
我还以为这是以前下雨时  用来遮盖康乃迪克州的东西
Oh, I thought that's what they used to cover Connecticut when it rains.
摩妮卡  这带子有录什么
Hey, what's on this videotape?
我不晓得  放进去看看
You got me. Let's put it in.
嗨  嘿
Hi.  Hey.
照这边  杰克  好
Over here, Jack. Okay.
瑞秋就要进门了
Rachel's coming up the path.
她是不是很美  杰克
Doesn't she look pretty? Jack?
你能拍到吗
Can you get this?
哦  我的天
Oh, my God!
你的鼻子怎么了
What is with your nose?
我当年有鼻中膈弯曲  后来只好弄短了
They had to reduce it because of my deviated septum.
我错了  用来遮盖康乃迪克的是这个才对
Okay, I was wrong. That's what they use to cover Connecticut.
知道是什么吗  这是我们准备要去毕业舞会的带子
This is us getting ready for the prom. Ah!
我们不要看这个  要  要看
We don't have to watch.  Yeah, we do.
要啦  很好玩的！
Come on! It's fun!
来拍摩妮卡
JUDY: Get a shot of Monica.
摩妮卡人呢  在这边  爸
Where's Monica? Over here, Dad!
等等  怎么拉远
Wait. How do you zoom out?
拍到罗
There she is!
有个女孩把摩妮卡吞掉了
Some girl ate Monica!
闭嘴  摄影机本来就会让人多十磅
Shut up! The camera adds ten pounds.
哇  有几部摄影机同时在拍你啊
So how many cameras are actually on you?
哦  你看起来好棒
Oh, you look so great!
你也是  你好美
RACHEL: So do you! You look beautiful!
哇  干嘛
Oops. What?
我的美乃滋沾到你了
I think I got mayonnaise on you.
只是肩膀  没沾到衣服
Oh, it's just the shoulder, not my dress.
大家  微笑
Everybody smile!
关掉！
Oh, Dad, turn it off!
哪有  红灯怎么还亮着  那是代表关掉的灯
It is off. It is not! What's with the red light?
是吧  罗斯
It's the off light. Right, Ross?
帅哦  科特尔先生
Looking good, Mr. Kotter.
你今夜看起来很美  哦  谢了
You look pretty tonight. Oh, thanks.
你这个暑假要做什么  我会留下来
What are you doing this summer? I'm gonna hang out...
弄我的音乐
...work on my music.
我的扣子松了吗  这些东东一直往下掉
Is my hook unhooked? These things keep falling down.
我看看  我不晓得
Let me see. I don't know.
你打算如何…
What are you gonna do...
男孩子到了
Oh! The guys are here!
过暑假
This summer?
弄你的音乐
Work on your music?
哦  我的天  是洛伊·贾柏立克
RACHEL: Oh, my God! There's Roy Gublik!
洛伊看了《星际大战》317次
You know, Roy saw Star Wars 317 times.
他还拿来写论文
His name was in the paper.
奇普人呢  他怎么还没到
Where's Chip? Why isn't he here yet?
他会来的  可以吗  吞颗镇定剂吧
He'll be here, okay? Take a chill pill.
好了
There.
我刚才是跟瑞秋说  洛伊碰了我的胸部
I just told Rachel that Roy touched my boob.
我没有舞伴不能去参加  我不能  来不及了
I can't go to the prom without a date. I can't! It's too late!
你不去的话  我也不想去
If you're not going, then I don't want to go either.
哦  我要宰了奇普
Oh, I'm gonna kick Chip's ass!
我有个好主意
I have a wonderful idea.
你应该带瑞秋去参加毕业舞会
You should take Rachel to the prom.
很怀疑呐
Doubtful.
杰克  摄影机给我  你来跟你儿子说
Jack, give me that. Talk to your son.
好  赶快  这东西很重耶
All right, go on. This thing's heavy.
你妈妈说的对  带她去  你可以穿我的礼服
Your mother's right. Take her. You can wear my tux.
她不会想跟我去的
She won't wanna go with me.
她当然愿意 你是大学生了
JACK: Of course she would! You're a college man!
我不晓得  哦  好了啦
I don't know. Well, come on.
你就不想试试看
Don't you wanna find out?
我真是不敢相信  我不能参加毕业舞会了
I can't believe I can't go to the prom!
太糟糕了
This is so harsh!
好  帮我拿键盘  好孩子  好孩子
Hold my board. Attaboy! Attaboy!
我想我们也看够了
I think we've seen enough.
可以关掉了  不  不  不
Let's turn it off.  No, no, no!
好  我不看了
Well, I'm not gonna watch.
快点  小鬼  咱们走
Come on, kid. Let's go!
哇  真是帅啊  给大家瞧瞧
My! Are you handsome! Let's show them!
等一下  爸
Just a sec, Dad.
好  要酷  要酷一点
Okay, be cool. Just be cool.
好了  爸
Okay, Dad.
瑞秋  准备好了没  你的白马王子来了…
Rachel, ready or not, here comes your knight in shining...
哦  糟了
Oh, no.
再见  不用等我们了
MONICA: Bye! Don't wait up!
奇普
RACHEL: Chip!
哦  真是
Oh, dear!
杰克  我怎么把这东西关了
Jack. How do I turn this off?
按下按钮
JACK: Press the button.
哪一个  哪个按钮  杰克
JUDY: Which one? Which button? Jack!
那一个  就那一个！
The button! The button!
没想到你愿意这样做
I can't believe you did that.
对  嗯
Yeah, well...
看到没  他是她的龙虾
See? He's her lobster!
跟他跳
JUDY: Dance with him!
妈  我饿了
Mom, I'm hungry!
跟你爸爸跳
Dance with your father.
我也许不会跳闪舞  不过我上了舞池亦非等闲之辈
I don't know any of your flashdances, but I'm no slouch on the dance floor.
好吧
All right.
哦  杰克  哦  茱蒂
Oh, Jack! Oh, Judy!
哦  菜蒂
Oh, Judy!